Resume H F Twelker

Heading

Full Name: Hans Fredrik Twelker Email: hans tw@hotmail.com Phone: +31 6 83 96 76 91

LinkedIn: https://nl.linkedin.com/pub/hans-twelker/6/426/413

GitHub: https://github.com/twelapps

Skills

Programming Languages: Swift; Objective-C; IBM's PL/S and Rexx

Frameworks: Apple's Cocoa Touch

IDEs: Apple's XCode

Version Control Systems: GitHub; IBM RYO version control system

Databases: relational databases such as IBM's SQL/DB2

Operating Systems: Apple iOS; Apple OS; MS Windows; IBM MVS and VM/S Networking: wired and wireless wide area and local area networks: TCP/IP

Projects

Development of an iOS app "Memory Buddy" and inclusion in Apple's AppStore

For storing images in an iOS Notes-like environment, now obsolete since Notes supports images as of iOS 8

Numerous projects at IBM and AT&T, refer to "Relevant Experience"

Relevant Experience



at&t (1999-2015)

- Technical Sales Consultant several new multi-million contracts and contract renewals (The Hague area, Netherlands, 2005-2015)
- Director Netherlands and Belgium, AT&T Solutions Center managing an international team of highly skilled network professionals (The Hague area, Netherlands, 2003-2005)
- Solutions Manager managing varying teams working on proposal development (The Hague area, Netherlands, 2000-2003)

15 (1984-1999)

- Proposal Manager managing proposal development (The Hague area, Netherlands, 1994-2000)
- Development Director managing up to 25 team members and several projects (Amsterdam area, Netherlands, 1989-1994)
- Software Developer RDM system (Amsterdam area, Netherlands, 1984-1989)

Education

Masters: University of Amsterdam, Theoretical Physics (with honors)

Nanodegree: Udacity iOS programmer (in progress)

Courses Taken: programming; project management; management while working for IBM

and AT&T

Interests

My interests are: iOS programming; making trips through US including Alaska and Hawaii, and Canada; rowing; cycling; running and walking

Awards, Publications, Presentations

Publications:

 On the non-relativistic limit of a spin-1/2 particle in a classical gravitational field (Physica A: Statistical and Theoretical Physics, 1984)